Finding Aid for University and Development Events (University of Michigan) Records, 1964-2015 (bulk 1983-1998)
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University and Development Events (University of Michigan) records 1964-2015 1983-1998
University of Michigan. University and Development Events.
0374 Bimu 2
Office responsible for planning and managing the university's official and ceremonial events, including commencements, faculty and student honors convocations, and development events such as University Seminars and President's Weekends; also manages operation of the President's House and Inglis House. Consists of files of events arranged by year including planning files, scripts, programs, guest lists, decoration, and event set up. Many event files include photographs; particularly University Seminars where faculty gave presentations to key university supporters. Some audiotapes are also included.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
15 linear feet
Records were received from this unit (donor number Donor 3813 ) beginning in November 2000. Periodic additions have been received.
The University and Development Events records are open for research.
The Office of University and Development Events is responsible for planning and managing the University of Michigan's official and ceremonial events. The office plans and coordinates approximately 100 events annually, including commencements, faculty and student honors convocations, official presidential and regental activities, and development events such as campaign activities and donor receptions and programs. This unit also has oversight for the President's House and Inglis House operations. Previously, many of these responsibilities fell on several other units. The Office of the Chief Marshall of the University, and that of the Secretary of the University both at one time oversaw the planning of commencement activities. Planning for various other events has fallen under the Office of the Assistant to the President and the Office of the Vice President for Development. The creation of an office of University and Development Events was an effort at centralizing and coordinating planning and logistics.
In early 1989 the Office of University Events was formally established. Anita Miller held the post designated at the time as Director of University Events and Assistant to the Secretary of the University. Responsibilities for development events and planning were gradually added to the position.
Records of the University and Development Events office include files on major recurring campus events as well as special dedications and occasions. Events files often contain planning materials, correspondence, programs, scripts, invitation lists, newspaper clippings, and photographs. Photographs often depict decorations and event setup as well as those in attendance. The records are arranged within two series: Event Files and Audio Material.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. University and Development Events.; University of Michigan. Vice-President for Communications.; University of Michigan. Vice-President for Development.; Inglis House (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Commencements.; University of Michigan. Honors Convocation.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
University of Michigan. University and Development Events.; University of Michigan--Commencements.; Inglis House (University of Michigan)
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
University of Michigan. University and Development Events.; University of Michigan--Commencements.; University of Michigan. Honors Convocation.; Henry Russel Award (University of Michigan)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Event Files
  The Event Files were maintained by the office in chronological order by event. The chronological arrangement has been maintained with records for each year's events alphabetically arranged by event title. Records contained in this record group predate the official creation of the office, giving evidence of the previously dispersed functions.
  Files for the years 1964 through 1980 contain only one event per year, almost exclusively the Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend of the President's Club. It should be noted for those researching this Club or this event, that it is continued after 1986 under the titles President's Fall Weekend, President's Spring Weekend, or President's Weekend.
  From 1981 forward a greater number and variety of events are represented each year. Regularly included are such events as commencement, honors convocation, state of the university reports, the Henry Russel Lecture, football season events and bowl games, University Seminars, Women's Seminars, groundbreakings or dedications, conferences, inaugurations, and President's Weekends. Typically the records include detailed planning materials for the event, correspondence, programs, tickets, scripts for speeches, itineraries, invitation lists, newspaper clippings, and photographs. Photographs often depict decorations and event setup as well as people. Audiotapes are available for some of the larger events and are noted in the inventory. Of note are folders with planning materials for Commencements for 1964, when the speaker was President Lyndon B. Johnson, and 1991, when the speaker was President George H. W. Bush.
  From 1985 forward, there are often folders entitled "Miscellaneous Development Events," "Miscellaneous University Events," or "Miscellaneous Events." These include planning materials for various events throughout the year often not included in individual event folders, although events with individual folders are sometimes represented in the Miscellaneous folders.
  University Seminars brought together key donors and friends of the university for special lectures and demonstrations by faculty and staff members. Most seminar files include schedules of activities, background on the presenters, and photographs of the faculty lecturers and candid shots of the attendees at lectures or receptions.
  - 1964
    - Commencement, Spring (Lyndon B. Johnson) (Box 1)
  - 1965
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting (Box 1)
  - 1967
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting (Box 1)
  - 1968
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting (includes photos) (Box 1)
  - 1969
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1970
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1971
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1972
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1973
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1974
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1975
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1976
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1977
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1978
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1979
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend and Spring Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1980
    - President's Club, Spring Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1981
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend and Spring Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1982
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
  - 1983
    - Football Season (Box 1)
    - Kellogg Eye Center Groundbreaking (includes photos of watercolor) (Box 1)
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend (Box 1)
    - State of the University Report and Awards Ceremony (Box 1)
    - Tappan Hall Groundbreaking (includes photos) (Box 1)
  - 1984
    - Football Season (Box 1)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 1)
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend and Spring Weekend (Box 1)
    - Sugar Bowl (Box 1)
  - 1985
    - Burn Center Groundbreaking (Box 1)
    - Football Season (Box 1)
    - President's Club, Annual Meeting/ Football Weekend and Spring Weekend (Box 1)
    - State of the University Report and Awards Ceremony (Box 1)
    - University Seminar
      - Faculty Reception (Box 1)
      - Photographs
        - February 21-23 (Box 1)
        - April 11-13 (Box 1)
        - April 25-27 (Box 1)
        - June 13-15 (Box 1)
        - September 12-14 (Box 1)
        - October 31-November 2 (Box 1)
        - November 21-23 (Box 1)
  - 1986
    - Chemical Sciences Building Groundbreaking (includes photos) (Box 1)
    - Commencement, Winter and Spring, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Football Season (Box 1)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 1)
    - President's Fall Weekend/ Spring Weekend (Box 1)
    - State of the University Report and Awards Ceremony (Box 2)
    - Tappan Hall Dedication (Box 2)
    - University Seminar
      - Faculty Reception (includes photos) (Box 2)
      - Photographs
        - February 6-8 (Box 2)
        - March 6-8 (Box 2)
        - April 3-5 (Box 2)
        - June 12-14 (Box 2)
        - September 11-13 (Box 2)
        - November 6-8 (Box 2)
        - November 13-15 (Box 2)
    - Women's Seminar (includes photos) (Box 2)
  - 1987
    - Campaign for Michigan Finale (Box 2)
    - Commencement, Winter and Spring, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Football Season (Box 2)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 2)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 2)
    - President's Fall Weekend/ Spring Weekend (Box 2)
    - Rose Bowl (Box 2)
    - Harold T. Shapiro Farewell (Box 2)
    - State of the University Report and Awards Ceremony (Box 3)
    - University Seminar
      - Faculty Reception (Box 3)
      - Planning and Photographs
        - March 12-14 (Box 3)
        - April 2-4 (Box 3)
        - April 23-25 (Box 3)
        - May 28-30 (Box 3)
        - September 10-12 (Box 3)
        - November 5-7 (Box 3)
        - November 12-14 (Box 3)
    - Women's Seminar (includes photos) (Box 3)
  - 1988
    - Big 10 Development Officers Conference (Box 3)
    - Commencement, Winter and Spring, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - James J. Duderstadt Inauguration (includes photos), 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Football Season, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Hall of Fame Bowl (Box 4)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 4)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 4)
    - Leadership Awards (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Development Events (includes photos), 6 folders (Box 4)
    - President's Spring Weekend (audiocassette in last box) (Box 4)
    - State of the University Report and Awards Ceremony
    - University Seminar (Box 5)
      - Faculty Reception (includes photos) (Box 5)
      - Photographs
        - April 7-9 (Box 5)
        - May 5-7 (Box 5)
        - September 8-10 (Box 5)
        - November 3-5 (Box 5)
    - Women's Seminar (Box 5)
  - 1989
    - Angell Society Dinner, New York, NY (Box 5)
    - F. X. Bagnoud Building/ Foundation (Box 5)
    - Commencement, Winter and Spring (includes photos), 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Big 10 Development Conference (Box 5)
    - Willard H. Dow Laboratory Dedication (Box 5)
    - Football Season (Box 5)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (includes photos) (Box 5)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Development Events (includes photos), 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous University Events (includes photos), 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous University Events (includes photos), 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Rose Bowl (includes photos), 3 folders (Box 6)
    - State of the University Report and Awards Ceremony (Box 6)
    - Task Force on University Events (Box 6)
    - University Seminar
      - Photographs
        - May 4-6 (Box 6)
        - September 28-30 (Box 6)
        - November 2-4 (Box 6)
    - Women's Seminar (Box 6)
  - 1990
    - Commencement
      - Spring (includes photographs; audiotape in last box), 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Winter (Box 6)
    - Michele Oka Doner Benches Dedication (Box 6)
    - Faculty Awards (includes photos) (Box 7)
    - Football Season (includes photos) (Box 7)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 7)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (includes photos) (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Development Events (includes photos), 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous University Events (includes photos), 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Partners in Leadership Receptions, October 19 and May 15 (Box 7)
    - Rose Bowl (Box 7)
    - U-M Update for Corporate Leaders (Box 7)
    - University Seminar
      - Photographs, April 26-28 (Box 7)
  - 1991
    - Angell Society Recognition Dinner (Box 8)
    - Commencement
      - Spring (George Bush), 2 folders (Box 8)
        (includes photos
      - Spring, Schools and Colleges (Box 8)
        (includes photos)
      - Winter (Box 8)
    - Faculty Awards (Box 8)
    - Football Season (Box 8)
    - Gator Bowl (Box 8)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 8)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous Events, 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Schembechler Hall Dedication (Box 8)
    - School of Public Health 50th Anniversary (Box 8)
  - 1992
    - An Afternoon with the Presidents, 175th Anniversary Panel (Box 8)
    - Celebrate Michigan Campaign Kickoff (Box 8)
    - Commencement
      - Spring (Box 8)
        (includes photos; audiocassette in last box)
      - Spring, Schools and Colleges (Box 8)
      - Winter (Box 8)
    - Faculty Awards (Box 8)
    - Football Season (Box 8)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 9)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 9)
    - Major Gifts Committee Reception (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Events, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Partners in Leadership Reception (Box 9)
    - Rose Bowl (Box 9)
    - Women's Seminar (Box 9)
  - 1993
    - Francois-Xavier Bagnoud Dedication (Box 9)
    - Commencement
      - Spring (Box 9)
      - Winter (Box 9)
    - East Engineering Renovation Groundbreaking (Box 9)
    - Faculty Awards (Box 9)
    - Football Season (Box 9)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 9)
      (includes photo; audiocassette in last box)
    - Holiday Reception (Box 9)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Events, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - New Student Convocation (Box 9)
    - Ovation Dinner (Campaign for Hill) (Box 9)
    - President's Weekend (Box 9)
    - Rose Bowl (Box 10)
    - University Seminar (Box 10)
    - William E. Simon Lecture-Carlos Salinas DeGortari, May 27 (Box 10)
  - 1994
    - Dance Event (Box 10)
    - Campaign Steering Committee (Box 10)
    - Commencement, Spring, Schools and Colleges (Box 10)
    - Faculty Awards (Box 10)
    - Football Tailgates (Box 10)
    - Hall of Fame Bowl (Box 10)
    - Henry Russel Lecture (Box 10)
    - Holiday Bowl (Box 10)
    - Honors Convocation (Box 10)
    - Inglis House (Box 10)
    - Mid Campaign Event, September 23-24, Book VII (Box 10)
    - Naples, Florida Reception and Dinner (Box 10)
    - New Student Convocation (Box 10)
    - ITIC "Media Union" Groundbreaking (Box 10)
    - Policy Seminars (Box 10)
    - President's Advisory Group Meeting/ Luncheon (Box 10)
    - President's Advisory Group Meeting/ Luncheon (December 7) (Box 10)
    - Richard Kennedy Reception (Box 10)
    - University Graduate Exercises I (Box 10)
    - University Seminar (Box 10)
    - University Seminar, October 27-29 (Box 10)
    - University Seminar, November 10-12 (Box 10)
    - Winter Commencement (Box 10)
    - Women's Seminar (Box 10)
  - 1995 (Box 11)
    - Alamo Bowl (Box 11)
    - Ara Paul Retirement (Box 11)
    - Central Galilee Dedication (Box 11)
    - Events Index (Box 11)
    - Faculty Awards, October (Box 11)
    - Football-Fall (Box 11)
    - Glacier Hills Seminar (University Seminar Series) (Box 11)
    - Henry Johnson Retirement (Box 11)
    - Henry Russel (Box 11)
    - Honors Convocation I (Box 11)
    - Inglis House Book (Box 11)
    - New Student Convocation, August 30 (Box 11)
    - New York Event, December 7 (Box 11)
    - Physics Research Lab Dedication, October 12-13 (Box 11)
    - President's Advisory Committee Group, May 5 (Box 11)
    - President's Weekend (Box 11)
    - Salk Polio Vaccine Anniversary (Box 11)
    - Shapiro Library Dedication (Box 11)
    - Smithsonian (Enola Gay) I (Box 11)
    - Spring Commencement I (Box 11)
    - University Gradate Exercises III (Box 11)
    - University Seminar (Box 11)
    - Women's Seminar (University Seminar Series) June 13 (Box 11)
    - Winter Commencement, December 17 (Box 11)
  - 1996
    - Regents Meeting and President Lee Bollinger's first UM Press Conference (Box 11)
      (audiocassettes only)
    - University Seminar (Box 11)
    - Arizona Events, March 20-22 (Box 12)
    - Duderstadt Recognition Dinner, May 2 (Box 12)
    - Faculty Awards Program, October 7-9 (Box 12)
    - Football (Box 12)
    - Henry Russel Dinner-Canceled, December 2 (Box 12)
    - Henry Russel Lecture, March 12 (Box 12)
    - Honors Convocation, March 24 (Box 12)
    - Huetwell Dedication, September 20 (Box 12)
    - Lurie Tower Dedication, October 17 (Box 12)
    - Media Union Dedication, June 21 (Box 12)
    - New Student Convocation, August 28 (Box 12)
    - Pierpont Naming Ceremony, February 16 (Box 12)
    - Presidents Weekend (Box 12)
    - Searle Recognition, October 24
    - Spring Commencement, May 4 (Box 12)
    - Staff Duderstadt Recognition Event, May 30 (Box 12)
    - University Graduate Exercises, May 3 (Box 12)
    - Winter Commencement, December 15 (Box 12)
    - Women's Seminar (Box 12)
  - 1997
    - Grand Rapids Reception-Hands Across the State, March 21 (Box 12)
    - Henry Russel Lecturers' Dinner, May 6 (Box 12)
    - Honors Convocation, March 16 (Box 12)
    - Outback Bowl, January 1 (Box 12)
    - Spring Commencement, May 3 (Box 12)
    - University Graduate Exercises, May 2 (Box 12)
    - University Seminar-Glacier Hills, June 19 (Box 12)
    - Women's Seminar, June 5 (Box 12)
    - Faculty Awards, October 13 (Box 13)
    - Football (Box 13)
    - Henry Russel Lecturers' Dinner, December 1 (Box 13)
    - Lee Bollinger Inaugural, September 19, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - New Student Convocation, September 2 (Box 13)
    - Tisch Dedications, September 25 (Box 13)
    - Winter Commencement, December 14 (Box 13)
  - 1998
    - Arthur Miller Dinner (Chez Josephine, New York), May 12 (Box 13)
    - Burnham House, Groundbreaking, May 15 (Box 13)
    - Florida Events, February 11-13 (Box 13)
    - Harlan Hatcher Memorial Service, March 1 (Box 13)
    - Henry Russel Lecturers' Dinner, March 10 (Box 13)
    - Honors Convocation, March 22, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Marshall Symposium, May 29-31 (Box 13)
    - Regents Reception (Grand Rapids) (Box 13)
    - Spring Commencement, May 2 (Box 13)
    - University Graduate Exercises, May 1 (Box 13)
    - William Bolcum Sixth Symphony Premiere (Kennedy Center, New York), February 28 (Box 13)
    - Women's Seminar Program, "Acts of Citizenship," May 20 (Box 13)
    - New Student Convocation (Box 13)
    - Ameritech Press Conference, September 2 (Box 13)
    - Faculty Awards, October 14 (Box 13)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, October 31 (Box 13)
    - Social Work Dedication, September 25 (Box 13)
    - Football Invitations, Recommendations, and Final Attendance Reports (Box 13)
    - Football MSU Tailgate, EMU Tailgate, Syracuse Tailgate (Box 14)
    - Henry Russel Black Tie Dinner, December 9 (Box 14)
    - Development Holiday/Roy Muir's Retirement, December 9 (Box 14)
    - Winter Commencement, December 20, 2 file folders (Box 14)
    - Museum Safari Group, October 9-10 (Box 14)
    - Inglis House Events, July-December (Box 14)
    - President's House Events, January-December (Box 14)
  - 1999
    - Citrus Bowl, January 1 (Box 14)
    - Henry Russel Lecture, March 9 (Box 14)
    - Honors Convocation, March 21 (Box 14)
    - University Graduate Exercises, April 30, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Spring Commencement, May 1, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Tanner Lecture Meetings, June 29-30 (Box 14)
    - 1999-2000 Event Notebook Index (Box 14)
    - New Student Convocation, September 1 (Box 14)
    - Football Invitations (Box 14)
    - Faculty Awards Dinner, October 6 (Box 15)
    - A. Alfred Taubman Naming, October 13 (Box 15)
    - G.R. Ford Press Conference and Lunch, November 18 (Box 15)
    - Henry Russel Black Tie Dinner, December 7 (Box 15)
    - Winter Commencement, December 19 (Box 15)
  - 2000
    - Henry Russel Lecture, March 14 (Box 15)
    - Honors Convocation, March 19 (Box 15)
    - University Graduate Exercises, April 28 (Box 15)
    - Spring Commencement, April 29, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - 2010
    - Spring Commencement and Honorary Degree Recipients Certificates and Citations (Box 15)
  - 2013
    - Faculty Awards, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Henry Russel Award (Box 15)
    - Winter Commencement Honorary Degree (Box 15)
  - 2014
    - Henry Russel Award (Box 15)
    - Winter Commencement Honorary Degree (Box 15)
  - 2015
    - Henry Russel Award (Box 15)
- Audio Material
  Audio Material includes recordings of various events on cassette tapes. The eleven audiocassette tapes date from 1988 to 1996.
  - Audiocassette Tapes
    - Board of Regents Meeting and President Lee Bollinger's first UM Press Conference November 12, 1996, 2 tapes (Box 11)
    - Commencement
      - Spring 1992 (Box 11)
      - Winter 1994, 2 tapes (Box 11)
    - President's Weekend Leadership Awards September 23, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Henry Russel Lecture and Award
      - March 16, 1993 (Box 11)
      - March 14, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Honors Convocation
      - 1993 (Box 11)
      - March 19, 1995 (Box 11)
    - New Student Convocation 1994 (Box 11)
Related Material
For additional event planning materials, researchers are advised to consult the records of the Chief Marshall, Secretary, Assistant to the President, and Vice President for Development, as well as the individual records of committees which may have overseen specific events.